# **GILLIAN YEOMANS**

# **Full-Stack Developer**

Portfolio: gillian.tech

Github: yeo-yeo

LinkedIn: gyeomans

Email: hello@gillian.tech

I am a former Risk Analyst, retrained as a Full-Stack Developer. I love learning new skills and technologies, and putting them to practical use with my business experience. I am based across London and Rome and enjoy yoga and crosswords.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Founders and Coders, London

18 week full-stack selective bootcamp with a focus on strong fundamentals (e.g. vanilla JS) and project work. Emphasis on pair programming and team mentality. TDD, agile and continuous integration tools used throughout.

The course culminates with a 3-week project for an external product owner: see details overleaf.

#### British Institute & My English School, Rome

English teacher working with individuals and groups of all ages and all levels: beginners, conversation, business, secondary school exams.

#### Nephila Advisors, London/Bermuda

Risk Analyst specialising in Nephila's Lloyd's insurance syndicate 2357, in team of 5 overseeing \$330m of GWP. My roles included financial modelling of natural catastrophe impact, operational liaison, underwriting analysis. I developed a number of processes and tools which are still in use 3 years after my departure.

#### Lloyd's of London

Graduate Programme in Lloyd's insurance market: rotations in Research, Market Analysis and external placement to Nephila syndicate 2357 in Bermuda.

# STACK

#### 2019-2020 **FE/BE**

HTML
CSS
JavaScript
React
Node.js
Express
PostgreSQL
Airtable
Google Maps

# 2017-2019

Jest Tape NYC Codecov

**TESTING** 

# 2015-2017

2013-2015

TOOLS
Git
Travis
Heroku
Netlify
AWS (CCP)

#### **DESIGN**

Figma Adobe XD

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Chatti

## DevOps Lead / Developer

HTML, CSS, React, Javascript, Express, PostgreSQL

- An app which provides parents with activities targeting early stages development goals
- DevOps responsibilities included: setting up the project architecture (React components structure, server, database) and continuous integration tools (Travis, Codecov)
- I was also active in organising the team's workflow (sprint planning, prioritising, reviewing Kanban board) and communication with the product owner
- My favourite parts of the project were:
  - implementing authentication (hashing passwords, creating/verifying JWTs, setting cookies)
  - 'connecting the dots' between the many different moving parts (React props/state management, fetch calls, database queries, rendering data)

https://chatti-app.herokuapp.com https://github.com/fac18/chatti

#### Signpost

#### QA Lead / Developer

HTML, CSS, React, Javascript, Express, Airtable

- A directory app which lists services for people at risk of homelessness
- One week design sprint and user testing using Figma and rapid prototyping, two oneweek development sprints
- I took the lead on implementing the Google Maps and Geocoding APIs, involving careful study of documentation and some lateral thinking to implement and customise in React
- As well as general development, I was responsible for implementing testing and maintaining a good quality of overall code

https://signpost-app.herokuapp.com https://github.com/fac18/signpost

#### VOLUNTEERING

#### Code Your Future, Rome

Education Team member of a bootcamp for refugees: responsible for organising the course and monitoring student development.

#### Codebar coach

Having attended Codebar as a student, I have recently started attending as a coach

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of Edinburgh

First Class MA (Hons) English Literature and Classics Roy M. Pinkerton Prize in Latin

#### University of Washington, USA

International exchange Annual Dean's List Meg Greenfield Essay Prize